Pranav Goel

Email: pranavgoel2012@gmail.com Figma: figma.com/@iipranavii Mobile: +91-9599091897 GitHub: github.com/iipranavii

Summary

Creating Beautiful Designs with Memorable Experiences. Focused on designing products that are both accessible and interactive. My passion for human-computer interaction helps me observe what most people forget, thus helping me create designs that are unique yet familiar to use. I love working with Colors and Abstract Designs.

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Design: Wire Framing, Low Fidelity, Prototypes, High Fidelity, Data Visualisation, Design Systems • Research: Storyboarding, User Research, Persona Development, User Journery, Usablilty Testing Figma, Zeplin, InVision, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Blender, GitHub, HTML/CSS • Tools: • Soft Skills: Leadership, Empathy, Writing, Collaboration, Critical and Creative Thinking

EDUCATION

Chandigarh University

Punjab, India

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science; GPA: 8.58

Sept 2020 - June 2024*

Courses: Cloud Computing, Data Structures, Analysis Of Algorithms, Microservices, Networking

Google UX Design Certification

Remote

User Experience and Interface Design

Oct 2021- May 2022

Courses: Moodboarding, Wireframing, Lo-Fi Design, User Research, High Fidelity Protoyping

EXPERIENCE

Quansight

Texas, USA (Remote)

UX Design Intern

July 2022 - Oct 2022

- o Accessibility Design: Researched on Accessibility in Data Visualisation and explored the nueances of WCAG Guidelines, incorporating them within future design systems.
- o Design System Research: Constructed a mood board for company-wide design system with accessibility focused design and typography.
- o Data Viz Mock-Ups: Implemented the Design System into currently used data visualisations, increasing visibility by 50% within the visually impaired TA.

PeakMind

Bengaluru, India (Remote)

Product Design Intern

Jan 2022 - July 2022

- Brand Identity Implementation: Built a design system for the company, Typography, Colours, Brand Identity.
- User Interviews: Conducted User Research analysing current scope of improvement and target audience comparisons.
- Web & App design: Designed Mobile App Mock-ups and Wireframes with extensively re-usable design components.

Projects

- SponsorBlok: (October 2021) StoryBloks, NextJS, AnimeJS, Figma
 - Created a cohesive platform for organizers and companies to reach out and avail sponsorships.
 - Designed the landing page and constructed a user journey for the service.
- FeedbackPrime: (October 2021) Symbl.ai, Kotlin, Sawo Labs, Figma
 - Built an intelligent system to understand and analyse the pain points during a customer support call.
 - o Designed an overnight UI to accept user's input and showcase a line-by-line output.

Honors and Achievements

- Selected as HackClub Leader Community for High school tech enthusiasts
- Awarded the title of Postman Student Expert.
- Won 1st Prize in API World Hackathon for Feedback Prime in Symbl.ai Challenge
- Won StoryBlok Track at Hack this Fall Hackathon for SponsorBlok
- Won the first-ever Postman API Fest

Volunteer Experience

India

Organiser - API Hacks Organized events, hackathon and conducted technical workshops reaching over 500 developers. Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

Co-Organiser - Friends of Figma

Jalandhar, India

Organized virtual workshop and worked on resources to help 100+ designers.

November 2022 - Present